Guide to the William S. Vickrey Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
William S. Vickrey Papers,
1939-1996
Vickrey, William S. (William Spencer), 1914-
23.5 linear ft. (ca 16,500 items in 47 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
5455879
Biographical Note
William S. Vickrey was born in 1914 in Victoria, British Columbia. After earning a B.S. in mathematics from Yale University in 1935, he went on to Columbia University where he earned an M.A. (1937) and Ph.D. (1947) in Economics. During World War II, Vickrey served as an economist in the Tax Research Division of the U.S. Treasury Department. In 1946, Vickrey began his teaching career at Columbia, eventually becoming the McVickar Professor of Political Economy in 1971. His research career was prolific with over 100 books and articles published on a broad range of matters and he worked as a consultant on projects in the U.S. and abroad. Vickrey lectured extensively, participated in numerous professional organizations, supported efforts for world peace, and served as president of the American Economic Association in 1992. Shortly before his death on October 11, 1996, Vickrey was awarded the Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic Sciences "for his fundamental contributions to the economic theory of incentives under asymmetric information."
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised of correspondence, manuscripts, teaching materials, conference materials, subject files, and printed items from William S. Vickrey's career as an economist. It contains published and unpublished papers illustrating his thoughts on various aspects of economic theory and their practical application. Topics discussed in these manuscripts involve macroeconomics, marginal cost pricing, microeconomics, political economy and welfare, public finance, social choice, taxation, transportation, urban economics, and related matters. The collection also has records from his tenure at Columbia University, including correspondence with his academic colleagues and participation in professional activities.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Columbia University
Series V: Conference Materials
Series VI: Subject Files
Series VII: Printed Material
Subjects
American Economic Association.; Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development.; Bonbright, James C. (James Cummings), 1891-1985.; Cordier, Andrew W. (Andrew Wellington), 1901-; Koch, Ed, 1924-; McGill, William J.; Melman, Seymour.; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003.; Muskie, Edmund S., 1914-1996.; Poitier, Sidney.; Shoup, Carl Sumner, 1902-; Thurmond, Strom, 1902-2003.; United States--Economic conditions.; New York (N.Y.); Economics.; Finance.; Economics--Methodology.; Macroeconomics.; Price regulation.; Resource allocation.; Public utilities.; Postal service.; Budget.; Economic policy.; Economists.; Full employment policies.; Employment (Economic theory); Inflation (Finance); Debts, Public.; Deficit financing.; Anti-inflationary policies.; Microeconomics.; Statics and dynamics (Social sciences); Welfare economics.; Finance, Public.; Social choice.; Taxation.; Income tax--United States.; Progressive taxation.; Transportation.; Urban transportation.; Transit, International.; Local transit.; Subways.; City traffic.; Tolls.; Local transit--Fares.; Local transit--New York (State)--New York--Finance.; Urban economics.; Land use.; Energy policy.; Periodicals
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
Cecile Vickrey, executrix, Gift, 17 September 1997.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  Correspondence sent to William S. Vickrey from senators, congressmen, and other economists. Includes letters from Carl Shoup to Vickrey and his colleagues at Columbia University. Arranged alphabetically by last name of sender.
  - Bonbright, James C. To William Vickrey, New York, NY, 22 Nov.-6 Dec. 1954, (2 page t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
    [Includes Bonbright's comments on Vickrey's draft of paper on Marginal Cost Pricing.]
  - Cordier, Andrew W. To Professor William S. Vickrey, New York, NY, 8 May 1969, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Koch, Edward I. To Friend, Washington, DC, 1969, (2 t.l.s. (rubber stamp signature) ) (Box 1)
  - McGill, William J. To Professor William S. Vickrey, New York, NY, 16 May 1974, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Melman, Seymour To Colleague, New York, NY, 28 June-4 Aug 1966, (2 t.l.s. (with enclosures) ) (Box 1)
  - Melman, Seymour To Professor William S. Vickrey, New York, NY, 1963-1966, (3 t.l.s. (with carbon replies and related materials) ) (Box 1)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P. To William Vickrey, New York, NY, 1991-1993, (2 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Muskie, Edmund S. To Professor William Vickrey, Washington, DC, 20 Aug. 1974, (2 page t.l.s. (with carbon reply) ) (Box 1)
  - Poitier, Sidney To Friend, New York, NY, 1 Oct. 1973, (2 page t.l.s. (rubber stamp signature) ) (Box 1)
  - Shoup, Carl S. To William S. Vickrey, [v.p.], 1948-1992, (2 a.l.s. 3, t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Shoup, Carl S. To Professors Albert G. Hart, Albert O. Hirschman, Peter B. Kenen, and William Vickrey, New York, NY, 6 Jan. 1961, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Shoup, Carl S. To Robert M. Haig, C. Lowell Harriss, William Vickrey, and William C. Warren, [n.p.], 28 March 1951, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
  - Thurmond, Strom To William Vickrey, Washington, DC, 23 June 1993, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  Correspondence to and from William S. Vickrey related to his career in economics. These letters include debates on economic theory, discussion of transportation issues, requests for references, proposals for grant projects, and reviews of other economists' papers. The series also has letters about symposiums, involvement with professional organizations, visits by other scholars, Quaker activities, publications, and comments by colleagues on his work. In addition, there is personal correspondence with his wife Cecile, mother, and friends. Arranged alphabetically by last name of sender.
  - A, 1964-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allan, Ron, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Council for an Energy-Efficient Economy, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Economic Association (AEA), 1948-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Economic Association (AEA), 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - :Appointments American Economic Association (AEA), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Economic Review, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Economic Review, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Economic Review, 1979-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Statistical Association, 1960-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arnott, Richard, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AT&T, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Atlantic Economic Society, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - : Reprint of Agenda for Progressive Taxation Augustus M. Kelley Publishers, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - B, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - B, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - B, 1980-1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bab, Herbert, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bagiotti, Tullio, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Barton, Allen H. 1973 & 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Baum, Sandra, 1982-1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Baumol, William, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Beckman, Martin J. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Beckwith, Burnham P. 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Bell Journal of Economics and Management Science, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benson, E. J. 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Berman, Dale, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bidwell, Miles O. 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bird, Richard M. 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Block, Walter, 1977 & 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bobbs Merrill Company, Inc., 1966 & 1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Boulding, Elise, 1968 & 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - British Consulate-General, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Butcher, William L. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - C, 1956-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - C, 1981-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Cairns, John, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Carr, Marjorie H. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Carroll, John J. 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Chamberlain, Neil W. 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Chase, Elmer P. 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Chinitz, Benjamin, 1969 & 1972 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Citizens Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Citizens Union of the City of New York, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - City Club of New York, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Colander, David, 1976-1982 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Columbia Institute for Tele-Information (CITI), 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Committee on Land Taxation (COLT), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Council of State Governments, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - D, 1957-1996 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Decker, Robert L. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Dikmen, M. Orhan, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Döen, Tom, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Downing, Paul, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Doyle, Richard D. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Dréave;ze, Jacques H. 1970-1994 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Duke University Press, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Dunn, LeRoy, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - E, 1965-1995 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Ecker-Racz, Laszlo, 1962 & 1967 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - The Econometric Society, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Econometrica, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Environmental Defense Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - F, 1963-1996 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Feldstein, Martin S. 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Foster, Christopher, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation (FCNL), 1980 & 1995 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - G, 1960-1996 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Gaffney, Mason, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Gannon, Colin A. 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Gawthrop, Paul R. 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Gigliotti, Gary, 1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Ginsburg, Helen, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Glenn, William A. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Gold, Andrew J. 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Goldin, Kenneth D. 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Gonzalez, Fernando, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Grieson, Ronald E. 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - H, 1962-1977 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - H, 1980-1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1965-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Harriss, Lowell, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Hau, Timothy, 1989-1995 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Hedges, Charles, 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Hertz, Roger J. 1968-1975 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Holden-Day, Inc., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Holland, Daniel M. 1952-1973 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Hunter, J. S. 1960 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - I, 1965-1996 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Ichimura, Shinchi, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - J, 1967-1995 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Jasinowski, Jerry, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Johnson, Byron L. 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Jones, Thomas H. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - The Journal of Business, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Journal of Political Economy, 1972-1983 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Journal of Transport Economics and Policy, 1966-1980 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Joy, Stewart, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - K, 1950-1993 (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Kalder, N. 1953 (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Kelly, John, 1993 & 1995 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Kennett, David, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Kohn, Robert E. 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - L, 1960-1975 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - L, 1980-1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Lambert, Ian, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Lave, Lester B. 1969 (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Lea, Norman D. 1959 (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - Lehmann, Glenn, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Levin, Harvey, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Levin, Harvey, 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Levin, Harvey, 1965-1975 (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - Levin, Harvey, Jan. 1976-June 1977 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Levin, Harvey, July 1977-Aug. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Levin, Harvey, Aug. 1977-May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Levin, Harvey, June-Dec. 1978 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Levin, Harvey, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Levin, Harvey, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Levin, Harvey, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Liu, Ta-Chung, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - M, 1960-1970 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - M, 1971-1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - McClintock, Deanne and Douglas, 1983-1992 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - MacLean, Brian, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 128)
  - Management Science, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 129)
  - Mathews, John A. 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - Mead, Edgar T. 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - Merewitz, Leonard, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - Milgram, Morris, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Modigliani, Franco, 1974 & 1993 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - Mohring, Herbert, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - Monash University, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - Morgan, Griscom, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Morse, Herbert C. 1966 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - N, 1958-1996 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - National Association of Railroad Passengers, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - O, 1963-1992 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Operations Research, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - P, 1966-1993 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - Palma, Andréde, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - Pan-Technology Consulting Corporation (PANTEK), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - Political Science Quarterly, 1966-1973 (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - Public Choice Society, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - Public Finance Quarterly, 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Public Finance Quarterly, 1975-1993 (Box 10, Folder 150)
  - Q, 1966-1983 (Box 10, Folder 151)
  - The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1974-1983 (Box 10, Folder 152)
  - R, 1959-1970 (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - R, 1971-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 154)
  - Rand Corporation, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - Reig, Enrique Jorge, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Review of Economic Studies, 1967-1974 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Richard D. Irwin, Inc., 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 158)
  - Rockefeller, Barbara, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 159)
  - Roth, Gabriel, 1971-1990 (Box 11, Folder 160)
  - Ruppenthal, Karl M. 1975 & 1981 (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - S, 1958-1969 (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - S, 1970-1989 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - S, 1990-1996, undated (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - St. Martin's Press, Inc., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - Sonstegaard, Miles, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 166)
  - Spillane, Annie, 1986-1991 (Box 11, Folder 167)
  - Steinberg, Charles, 1952-1970 (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - Straszheim, Mahlon R. 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - T, 1964-1996 (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Thomson, Ian, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 171)
  - Tideman, Nicolaus, 1968-1996 (Box 11, Folder 172)
  - Transportation, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 173)
  - TRED (Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development), 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - TRED (Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 175)
  - TRED (Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development), 1971-1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 176)
  - : Carter Weld TRED (Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development), 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 177)
  - : Carter Weld TRED (Committee on Taxation, Resources and Economic Development), 1969-1974 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - U, 1988-1993 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - United Nations, 1968-1975, undated (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - United States Treasury Department, 1972-1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - Urban Studies, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - V, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Vickrey, Cecile, 1968-1975 (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - Vickrey, Mrs. Charles V. 1970-1975 (Box 12, Folder 185)
  - W, 1954-1996 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Wheatcroft, G. S. A. 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Wilson, Douglas, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - Winter, Ernst F. 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 189)
  - Wohl, Martin, 1969 & 1971 (Box 12, Folder 190)
  - X, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 191)
  - Y, 1966-1982 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - Yance, Joseph V. 1968 (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - Z, 1969-1992 (Box 13, Folder 194)
  - Unidentified, 1949-1996 (Box 13, Folder 195)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  Typescripts, mimeograph masters, drafts, outlines, notes, and fragments of William S. Vickrey's papers, articles, reviews, and other economic documents. Various aspects of economic theory and application are discussed including macroeconomics, marginal cost pricing, microeconomics, social choice, taxation, transportation, urban economics, and related matters. Arranged alphabetically by subject designated by economic graduate students who previously inventoried Vickrey's papers or assigned by the author in his annotated bibliography. Many of the notes were also provided by Vickrey or the graduate students.
  - Subseries III.1: Macroeconomics
    Papers, letters to the editor, reviews, essays, speeches, and incomplete parts of Vickrey's book Metastatics and Macroeconomics. These papers focus mainly on government fiscal policy regarding balanced budgets, deficits, capital spending, unemployment, inflation, and social security. Also includes discussion of the fallacies of financial fundamentalism, markup warrants, interest rates, and related topics. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Acceptance of Honorary Membership in NTA, speech, 6 Nov. 1993 (Box 13, Folder 196)
      [Argues for a larger deficit.]
    - All That Anguish Over a Phony Number, letter to editor, 12 Dec. 1995 (Box 13, Folder 197)
    - Averting Unemployment and Inflation in Transition to Market Economy, paper, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 198)
    - Balanced Budget is Not the Answer, paper, 2 June 1992 (Box 13, Folder 199)
    - Balancing the Budget is a Recipe for Economic Disaster, paper, Feb-May 1995 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Budget Balancing: A Cruel, Pious Fraud, letter to editor, undated (Box 13, Folder 201)
    - The Burden of the Public Debt: Comment, article, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 202)
      [Published in American Economic Review, 51, March 1961, 132-7. Superseded by later analysis.]
    - Capital Budgeting, Unemployment, and Inflation, paper, June 1992 (Box 13, Folder 203)
      [Paper for Levy Institute Meeting, Bard College, 25 June 1992. Discusses alternative criteria for defining a capital budget and the need for marketable markup warrants. The appendix is about the detailed operation of the markup warrant proposal.]
    - Chock-full Employment without Increased Inflation, paper, Jan. 1991 (Box 13, Folder 204)
      [For presentation at session entitled "Achieving High Employment without Inflation", New Orleans, 4 Jan. 1991.]
    - Chock-full Employment without Inflation, paper, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 205)
      [Presented at Munich Conference 18 May 1992 and Prague/Bratislava Meetings 28 June-3 July, 1992.]
    - Comments on "Investment, Dividend, and External Finance Behavior of Firms" by Phoebus J. Dhrymes and Mordecai Kurz and on "Business Fixed Investment: A Marriage of Fact and Fancy" by W. H. Locke Anderson, review, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 206)
      [Shows a knowledge of econometrics.]
    - Controlling Inflation through Marketable Gross Markup Rights, paper, Dec. 1993 (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Controlling Inflation through Marketable Gross Markup Rights for Chock-full Employment in a Neo-Keynesian Economy, paper, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - Debt Limits Throttle the Economy, essay, 14 Nov. 1995 (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Debts, Deficits, and Delusions, paper, 14 Dec. 1990 (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - Disarmament, Unemployment, Budget, and Inflation, paper, June 1992 (Box 14, Folder 211)
    - The Dole Tax Plan Could Backfire, essay, 16 Aug. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 212)
    - Economic Criteria for Optimum Rates of Depletion, paper, [1967] (Box 14, Folder 213)
      [Appears to have been published in Extractive Resources and Taxation. Edited by Mason Gaffney. Milwaukee: University of Wisconsin Press, 1967. Discusses implications of the perfect information model.]
    - Effective Fiscal Policy, paper, 23 May 1993 (Box 14, Folder 214)
    - Fallacies of the Conventional Wisdom, notes for a talk, 26 Oct. 1992 (Box 14, Folder 215)
      [Notes for a talk at Marymount.]
    - Fatal Fallacies about Economies with Unemployment, paper, 6 Sept. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 216)
      [See also Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Establishment Economics, Box 14, Folder 217 and Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Fundamentalism, Box 14, Folder 218.]
    - Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Establishment Economics, paper, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 217)
      [See also Fatal Fallacies about Economies with Unemployment, Box 14, Folder 216 and Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Fundamentalism, Box 14, Folder 218.]
    - Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Fundamentalism, paper, 7 Sept. 1995 (Box 14, Folder 218)
      [See also Fatal Fallacies about Economies with Unemployment, Box 14, Folder 216 and Fifteen Fatal Fallacies of Financial Establishment Economics, Box 14, Folder 217.]
    - Fiscal Policy in Prosperity and Depression: Discussion of Papers Delivered by Musgrave and Hardy, review, Dec. 1947 (Box 14, Folder 219)
    - Fiscal Strategies for Shifting Resources from Military to Civilian Activities, paper, [1964?] (Box 14, Folder 220)
    - A Growing Debt is a Necessity, not a Threat, letter to the editor, 31 May 1995 (Box 14, Folder 221)
      [Response to letter by Congressman Mark W. Neumann, 24 May 1995.]
    - How Big a "Deficit" Do We Need?, essay, 28 June 1993 (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - How Successful as Innovators Have Economists Been?, paper, 9 Aug. 1987 (Box 14, Folder 223)
      [See also My Innovative Failures in Economics, Box 32, Folder 576.]
    - How to Get Real Full Employment (Jobs for All), paper, 8 Aug. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - Interest and Policy: Long or Short?, essay, undated (Box 14, Folder 225)
      [Discusses which interest rate to use in analysis of long-term projects.]
    - Letter on Budget Balancing, letter to the editor (Box 14, Folder 226)
    - Letter to Senator, 1 June 1993 (Box 14, Folder 227)
      [Discusses government deficit.]
    - Letter to The New York Times, letter to the editor, 30 Oct. 1992 (Box 14, Folder 228)
      [Discusses government deficit and full-employment economy.]
    - Letter to The New York Times, letter to the editor, 22 April 1993 (Box 14, Folder 229)
      [Argues against the Federal Reserve Board worries of overheating economy.]
    - Long Term Forecasting in Terms of Government Debt, paper, June 1994 (Box 14, Folder 230)
      [A reasonably complete articulation of the deficit view. The paper discusses the failure of market to equilibrium, interest-insensitivity of investment, and markup warrants in an open economy.]
    - Lowering Inflation through Gross Price Markup Rights, essay (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Macroeconomic Aspects of Tax Incidence, abstract of paper, Nov. 1994 (Box 14, Folder 232)
      [Abstract of paper for NTA Meetings, 13-16 Nov. 1994]
    - Macro-economic Impacts of Social Security, paper, April-May 1996 (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - A Macroeconomic Program for the Clinton Era, paper, [1992?] (Box 14, Folder 234)
      [Paper for the Annual Meeting of the Southern Economic Association, Washington, 23 Nov. 1992. The paper discusses the rapid growth to genuine full employment, then maintenance of full employment by strong fiscal measures under control of an anti-inflation program such as markup warrants.]
    - Markup Market, letter to the editor, 6 Feb. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 235)